Finding Aid for Lucy E. Chapin papers, 1834-1910
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lucy E. Chapin papers 1834-1910
Chapin, Lucy E., 1835-1910.
1 linear foot
2 oversize volumes
85961 Aa 2; AC
Ann Arbor, Michigan, resident and local historian. Collected Washtenaw County historical documents and scrapbooks of clippings, programs, photographs, and memorabilia.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from the Lucy Chapin estate (donor no. 1274 ) and from the Washtenaw Historical Society (donor no. 945 ). A few items came from Ethel Green (donor no. 3966 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Lucy Chapin was a local historian of Ann Arbor, Michigan.
The Lucy Chapin collection includes collected letters and manuscripts, most notably papers of James Kingsley, Washtenaw County public figure and member of the Board of Regents of the University of Michigan. Of great importance are the scrapbooks maintained by Lucy Chapin on the people and events of Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County. These scrapbooks document life in the nineteenth century from the 1840s to 1900. The volumes include clippings, programs, photographs, and memorabilia.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Business records.; Kingsley, James, 1797-1878.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Woodbridge, William, 1780-1861.; Ann Arbor's earliest select school.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Breed House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Volney Chapin House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Danforth House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Godfrey House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); James House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Kingsley House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Kingsley, James, 1797-1878.; Loomis House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Lund House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); MacIntyre House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Maynard House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Morgan House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Porter House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Pulcipher House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Miles-Sinclair House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Vail House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Wheeler House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Wilson-Wahr House (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Contributors:
Ransom, Epaphroditus, 1797-1859.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Letters, manuscripts, etc.
  - James Kingsley papers
    - Letter from William Woodbridge 1835 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence regarding his law practice (Box 1)
    - Receipts and miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Collected documents (Box 1)
    (include John Allen land memorandum, petition regarding insolvency of Washtenaw County debtors, and document pertaining to Bank of Washtenaw)
  - Paper entitled "Ann Arbor's Earliest Select Schools" (Box 1)
  - Photographs, mainly Ann Arbor residences (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook of clippings photographs, postcards, etc. relating to Ann Arbor buildings, residents, and events, 1 volume in 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks containing Ann Arbor newspaper business advertisements, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of Ann Arbor theatrical and musical programs and notices 1880s, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook primarily relating to the University of Michigan circa 1877-1885, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook primarily relating to the University of Michigan circa 1886-1896, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of clippings photographs, correspondence, and other documents relating to the career of James Kingsley, February 11, 1980 (Volume 1)
    (include letter from Epaphroditus Ransom, 1849)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and memorabilia relating to Ann Arbor events and personalities with many clippings re: Ann Arbor churches and schools 1840s-1940s (Volume 2)
    (include Bank of Washtenaw bank notes)